November 22, 1963, 12:38 pm - A trauma patient is rushed to Parkland Memorial
Hospital in Dallas. His name is President John F. Kennedy.
Parkland is a history, drama film directed by Peter Landesman.
November 22nd, 1963 was a day that changed the world
forever — when young American President John F.
Kennedy was assassinated in Dallas, Texas.
This film follows, almost in real time, a handful of individuals forced to make split-second decisions
after an event that would change their lives and forever alter the world’s landscape.
Jim Carrico, played by Zac Efron.
Doris Nelson, played by Marcia Gay Harden.
Abraham Zapruder, played by Paul Giamatti.
Forrest Sorrels, played by Billy Bob Thornton.
Marguerite Oswald, played by Jacki Weaver.
James Hosty, played by Ron Livingston.
Parkland  is a 2013 American historical drama film that recounts the chaotic
events that occurred following the 1963 assassination of John F.
The film was written and directed by Peter Landesman, in his directorial debut, and produced by Playtone's Tom
Hanks and Gary Goetzman, Bill Paxton, and Exclusive Media's Nigel Sinclair and Matt Jackson.
The film is based on Vincent Bugliosi's 2008 book Reclaiming
History: The Assassination of President John F.
The film explores themes of fbi, john f. kennedy, dallas,
texas, hospital, john f. kennedy assassination.
The tone is emotional.